Hello and welcome back to the Latent Space.
I'm Katie Roberts.
I'm here all day, and now we have Lars Trieloff.
He is a principal principal scientist.
Sorry.
Adobe working on cloud native content and API first architectures.
And you are going to be talking about this exciting building
AI agents in the browser for the browser of the browser.
This is hugely exciting talk, so please give it up for Lars.
Thanks everyone.
So every every story has to start somewhere.
And this story starts with inspiration.
And inspiration has to to meet you somewhere
and for unexplainable reasons,
inspiration hit me.
Well you're going to see where it hit me.
It hit me right here in the Ikea restaurant,
holding a hot dog and a soft serve ice cream.
And I was thinking of lobsters,
OpenClaw in particular. And
I've been I've been equally fascinated
and scared by this particular species of lobster.
One, because it gives it.
It is the dream of the agent, right?
It is such an intelligence that is just able to live in the world,
in the world that matters to you, in this case
your computer, your Mac mini, and control it.
But at the same time, this is also very, very scary.
Which is why people have been thinking about how can we constrain this power,
how can we put it in harness, how we can can we put it in a container?
And this was exactly the thought that I had.
And I knew, I knew of, of OpenClaw.
I knew of NanoClaw, which is putting this idea of a claw
inside a little container, almost a Docker container.
But then I remembered, number one, I hate Docker and dealing with it,
and I don't want this to be installed in my system.
One of the reasons is my system is under enterprise management,
so it is going to find out if I'm installing Docker
and they're going to send me an email where I need to justify myself.
And as much as I like hot dogs and ice cream,
I really hate justifying myself to it. And
the second,
the second part of it was that I thought, hey, I've got a container at home,
I've got a browser, and the browser is pretty self-contained.
It couldn't we couldn't we combine.
So the this,
this notion of where is the agent and how is it
constrained is a two sided thought. Right.
We want the agent to be in a box.
But on the other hand, every time we put the agent in the box,
it becomes less useful and less powerful.
So the the interesting thing for me
is that the box where most of my work happens
happens to be a web browser, like I'm using working in a big company.
So we have literally thousands of SaaS applications,
most of which I never have to use, some of which
I use regularly and withdraw, and some of them
I have to use every couple of months, and I
despise it. So,
the other thing
is, I've noticed that a lot of applications that we are building
are essentially putting agents in a little sidebar next
to whatever product you're building on. Right.
And this is essentially the the step of agent enablement.
You think of your existing UI.
And if you think, wouldn't that be great?
If we had a sidebar with an agent sitting right next to it?
And I think the canonical implementation of this is is copilot,
you have it sitting
next to you about document and you ask it, can you revise that?
Well document and copilot the same I'm sorry I don't know which
well documented talking about or you haven't been Gemini
in in Google Docs and it says, yeah, I know exactly what document
you're talking about.
I can see it. Sorry.
I can edit it.
And and then you have tools where you say,
actually, I have some of my information in slack.
I have other information in GitHub, I have other information here and there.
And whenever it comes to connecting these, it's not just enough
that I want it, and it's not just enough that the age of it.
It's also that the interconnection needs to be implemented
by whoever built the agent harness, and it needs to be enabled by it.
And it, at least in my case, is very cautious and very slow
in approving these things.
So we are, we are still waiting to roll
out, Copilot functions. So
my idea
was, what if we have one agent that is sitting in the browser
that is able to connect to all of my tools, right.
That is just able to talk to all of these who whatever APIs they have.
And when you think about this.
What are the APIs that web applications have?
These APIs are typically things like HTTP,
JSON, HTML, a bit of Dom,
a bit of here and bit of there, and we can figure it out. And.
We also have the problem that if we give access
to all of these tools, that the agent doesn't know how to deal with all of that,
some of the APIs the agents are
and the models, I should say, are intimately familiar with.
Right.
You can say, hey, just start remote controlling slack.
And the only thing it asks you, what is your token on other APIs?
It's going to say, hey,
I've never heard of this strange thing that you cooked up there.
How do I deal with this?
And this is where skills come.
This is where skills come to play, right?
And skills really come.
The agent from theoretically powerful.
A powerful
machine into a practically powerful machine.
So how do we how do we get started with this?
And the.
The idea that I came up with was an agent that is sitting in the browser.
It's actually running in the browser, which means it's not a cloud runtime
where the agent loop runs and you're just displaying in the browser,
but it's actually the actual agent loop is in the browser.
To close the browser tab, the agent loop starts,
and at the same time this agent should be able to control itself.
It should control it should
it should control the browser that it's running inside.
And this is how I come up with this notion of the self licking ice cream cone.
And and that's why you find it at slcc
slcc.com
and and there and while building it
there are a bunch of things that I was absolutely sure.
Well it's a browser right.
It can display HTML pages.
But there are a lot of things that it suddenly cannot do right.
So cannot transcode videos.
It suddenly cannot access my local file system.
But I'm fine with these constraints.
But in reality, I found during this exploration
that there are so many things
that my browser can do that I didn't even dare to think about.
And that was one of the things that made this exploration extremely fun.
And now you're wondering what this what this slide means.
And this slide means that I haven't been showing
you a presentation for the past ten minutes.
I've been showing you Slick.
I've been showing you the very agent that we are going to talk about.
And let's let's flip the instruction manual around
and move it back to move it back to the sidebar.
So and
one of the big ideas in slick
is this idea of ad hoc generated user interfaces.
Right.
We've been hearing how software is becoming,
how software is becoming very, very easy to build.
And I'm saying, yeah, it's becoming disposable.
Like you can build software that is good for just one presentation.
And, and this, this particular slide here, which is using three.js
and which is using which is using weird animations is exactly that, right?
It's a one off.
It's a one of it's a one off
application. And.
How many are we.
And I just hope that
that Slick is not going to judge me for my terrible typing.
Hello to all 80 of you in the latent space.
It's a pleasure to finally meet the humans I've only heard about through Lars.
Thanks for coming.
Okay,
well, it took it took say very literally. And.
And if you know that, say it's actually a command on sales,
actually a command on, on macros that I thought was fun.
So I had it poured it over.
And with this we can continue and go into the first
can go into the first into the first concept.
And these are sprinkles.
Yeah.
And sprinkles are essentially HTML files
running in an iframe that are being loaded in the sidebar.
So I'm slipping around this concept of oh yeah, the agent is on the sidebar.
No, the apps on the sidebar, the agent is the main thing,
and it has the ability.
It has the ability to
it has the ability to,
it has the
ability to self inspect what sprinkles are there, open sprinkles and so on.
And one of the most interesting things is, is that there's interactivity
or interaction between the sprinkles and the agent itself.
So whenever I advance the slide, I said send an event over to the agent.
This event is called LIC because we are talking about ice cream here.
And and this is how you see, this is how you see the agent commenting
on every single commenting
on every single on every single slide is controlling.
I've had applications where I said, yeah, you know,
you know what, we are just going to have a button.
And when you click the button,
you just tell
the agent that the button has been clicked and the agent is going to find out
what to do next, right? So and
I think I have a
so here we have an example of this
which is I can I can click a button here.
This is sending an event to this.
Sending an event to slick.
And Slick is then saying, yeah, what is the cone in the Slick architecture.
Well the cone that's the piece.
That's the piece of the ice cream
that you that is the user interface that you're interacting with.
And and it can either,
it can either change the UI on the fly or just spawned in the chat.
So the.
Here we go.
Here's my let's bring this back to full screen.
So and to make this to make this fun,
one of the additional things that we have in selected not so fast.
One of the additional things that we have in Slick is,
is that licks cannot just be fired from inside the sprinkle,
but you can also have a cron job as the link, right?
If you in case you want to have a repeated jobs, you can have
you can also register a webhook, which is basically a public URL
that whenever an HTTP requests
coming in, is sending an event over to either the cone
or to one of the sub agents. And
now, yeah.
So that okay, so,
We do have the
so the.
Dammit.
Oh, interesting. Okay.
So I, I broke something the, the the webhooks
actually working through, through WebRTC using WebRTC gateways.
Sometimes it's going to sleep and it's forgetting about it.
It doesn't matter.
Okay, here we go.
So the QR code has been replaced.
I think the QR code might not work, but, but that doesn't.
Oh, here we go.
Right.
So, you might be able to try this.
There's a chance that they are not going to come through.
Oh. It's localhost.
Again.
Yeah. I'm not you know what?
I'm going to skip this and I'm not going to reload this.
But we actually have so we have a, a host on silicon
AI which allows us to have non log.
Right. Sending you to localhost
is basically giving you
public public webhooks, which is really useful
if you're doing things like browser automation.
Right.
Let's say
you want to have a notification whenever a new slack message is coming in.
The way you would build, that is, you would intercept, new slack messages
in the slack application and say in JavaScript, say every time
that happens, just send a post to that particular webhook,
which is then going to which is then going to the agent. And.
We you've already seen you've already seen dips.
Dips.
It's the same idea, just much, much faster, much, much shorter.
It's rendering that HTML writing the chat again, it's a it's an iframe.
So it's properly isolated.
But it gives you this real time interactivity right here and there.
And now why are we holding
ice cream cones now hand at all.
And the answer is of course because they contain ice cream schools.
And the same thing is true here.
So in slick we have the ability to have some agents.
Some agents are called scoops.
And and I can I can show you.
So we had a couple of I don't know what it did.
So we have five scoops here.
We have an Ikea presentation.
We have a poet that shipped a haiku,
mathematician that shifted Dunbar calculation.
And the comedian that shaped a joke. Okay.
80 people is approximately Dunbar's number divided by two.
Well, okay.
Nice, I.
Okay, so here's another scoop.
This is the conference agenda scoop that I just said.
Get going.
And it's actually starting to work on this in the background
so I can continue with my with my presentation.
And let's see, let's see how optimistic or pessimistic slickers
with regards to to the scoop capabilities.
So let's talk a bit about architecture.
How does this how does this work.
And there
there are a couple of they essentially four pieces that I want to talk about.
The first one is this
this mushy mass that we have
here, which is the right and slick supports.
Essentially any LLM that you can think of.
We have we have support for your Codex subscription,
for your copilot subscription for your ex AI grok subscription.
You can bring your anthropic API key, you can bring your bedrock
API key, open root and a bunch of others.
And the better the model you pick, the more fun
you're going to have with slick.
One of the things that I built in there to make sure that you're not having
a bad time is, and preventing all mini and nano models from running the cone.
You.
The cone can still delegate these models for a sub agent,
but you never want this to be your main agent because your main agent
is is powerful and you don't want somebody stupid to be powerful.
The the second piece is the agenda group,
and the agenda group is powered by Pi agent, which is exactly the same agent
and written originally by Mario Zechner,
which is powering OpenClaw, which is also powering NanoClaw.
There's going to be a talk about Pi in detail
this afternoon, so I can fully recommend it.
It's a fantastic system and I've I've been using Pi
as an framework for months before I even started
using it as a or looking into it as, as a coding agent.
The next piece of this is the is the terminal.
And you've seen you've seen these little
you've seen these little commands that have been running here.
Some of these sprinkle commands.
But if we go back just a bit, we see for instance
here, this is this is where we actually call
this is where we actually call a bash, a bash command.
And I can open the terminal.
And I'm not going to say test, test, test again.
And we can see
we can see everything that's running here.
Here we go.
We have a list of skills.
Here you go.
Actually, we actually have a GitHub skill.
And you can run you can run git inside.
You can run git inside the browser as well.
This is powered by isomorphic git which is a tiny git implementation of JavaScript.
Really cool and elegant.
And the the last piece of the architecture
quickly want to show is.
You see this?
You see this cock wheel at the bottom.
It's really important because this is a web browser.
When I first started building this, basically everything was running nicely
in the main thread, which was fantastic because it was super simple architecture.
And then I started doing things like, let's pull
in, let's, let's open the,
the code directory where Slick's code itself is located.
And I'm using block trees for essentially every single feature.
And most of the time I don't delete them
after I'm done and I'm keeping them in the same directory.
So when I then said, hey slick, look in your own source code and find this
particular thing, Slick said, hey, I'm just going to run find.
What I didn't know was that find was running over
a 50 gigabyte huge directory, right?
Dozens of dozens of work trees.
Many, many, many, many copies of node modules.
And that wasn't just slow.
It completely froze. The main,
completely froze the rendering.
I thought, oh my God, oh my God, what is happening?
Figure it out quite easily.
But one of the cool things about this is that with this
we get, with this we actually get a process management
so I can run PS.
Here we go.
I can, I can run PSA, and it's actually giving me
all of the prompts and all of the commands that have been run
since the, should I say the system booted.
No, actually since page on load. Right.
I think that's the that's the correct term.
So it, it's giving us it's giving us
the ability to interrupt processes
whenever they are going.
Yes. It's the presentation.
So back to the presentation.
The, the next part of this is that
the protocols that are powering slick are really interesting.
So first of all, and I should mention it
because it's obvious is HTTP right.
So we are we're accessing it through HTTP.
And and
and HTTP is what the agent is using to interact with the rest of the world.
It has the ability to run curl.
It has the ability to, to to see the world through curl.
Right.
Secondly, it is the Chrome DevTools Protocol.
So through the Chrome DevTools Protocol it is then able to do things like opening new
tabs, controlling tabs, changing the font in a tab and and so on.
So the Chrome DevTools Protocol again is is extremely powerful protocol.
And the way how slick works with it is
Slick has a Playwright CLI installed.
Oh well it has something that looks like Playwright client is like it's
actually just a very, very tiny rapper around the CDP protocol,
like the real Playwright CLI.
So I had the opportunity to look into Playwright CLI to find out
that the that the mysterious substance that they're cooking with
is actually water.
We have
we have additionally WebRTC as a key protocol and WebRTC
is what enables the what enables the remote links that you've seen before.
The thing that didn't work because it didn't reload properly
and freely, we might, you know,
we might run.
So we can we can try that later.
But WebRTC allows us to take multiple
Slick instances and connect them together.
This is especially powerful because we have a tool called Slick Start.
And slick start allows you to not just to start
to start Chrome with slick enabled,
but it's also able to find all of the it's also able to find all of the electron
apps that you are running, and it's then able to run, launch
these electron apps in debug mode and inject the loading code,
the bootstrap code for slick into this electron app.
Really powerful, especially if you have things that you want to access.
And funny thing is, breaking into slack was super easy.
Really child's play.
And the hardest to break into was Claude and I was
I was completely surprised by this
because I thought, hey, this is a vibe coded application.
How can how can they have these security guards
and they have electrons users, which are essentially triggers that kill the binary.
Whenever you notice somebody's trying to access the debug port,
really cool engineering.
Turns out the person who wrote electron is working for anthropic,
and he's working on and he's working on, on the cloud desktop application.
But I can still break into it because we can patch the
we can patch the binary, remove the fuzes and create you.
Right.
So you can you can just do things.
And I'm getting I'm getting time checked here.
So where were we.
We were talking about tools.
There's a full box of there's a full toolbox available here.
Right. We have we have
we have bash and everything you would expect from core U-boats.
We have SQLite, we have a Python interpreter there.
We have image magic in there.
We have tools for dealing with with PDFs.
Last week I've added support for I've added support for biome
and the TypeScript compiler because,
Slick was opening pairs against slick, of course, but all of these were failing
in the linting step because we felt that in the last session spreading sloppy code.
So I'm giving slick a Linda that it can, that it can run inside,
inside the inside the the sandbox.
And we also have support for MCP.
How does MCP support work?
Well, in the end there's an MCC.
Don't know what's happening here.
There's an MCP command line which allows you to add an MCP URL.
And I'm only supporting right there.
There are multiple transports for for MCP.
Still the most common is standard in standard out
which I don't support but I support the Https based transport.
So if you have an MSC server somewhere you can use it.
Max is going to talk about MCC
later on when CP is also something that can be supported and slick.
Actually getting WebMCP support into Slick is just tell
slick hey, search for web MCP support.
It's going to find the fitting skill.
It's going to say, oh yeah, WebMCP is really easy.
It's just another property on the document that I can interact with that.
And we have.
We have I mentioned,
you know what I I'm running my slides out of order here.
But you've already heard about remote controlling slack remote
controlling teams.
Remote controlling
I don't know what email client that is that is running in in electron.
But you can probably probably actually teams is one of these that.
Yeah the icons though.
So the the last the last part
that I quickly want to talk about is
we have an oath token command.
And I think the best way to talk about
this is to,
Oh, yeah.
So, Okay.
Perfect.
Look at look at this.
So we have all of, we have all of token as a little command line and o off token
allows you to go through the of flow
and keep the token stored.
And we actually hiding the tokens from the lens
so that they never actually leak into the context.
Which leaves me with one last slide, which is,
let's get Slick to take a photo of me.
And, you know,
everyone knows how to take a photo on the command line if you run ffmpeg,
and then to open this folder to look at it,
and finally to deliver,
to deliver a roast of whatever Slick is seen here.
Three shades of black, a headset mike, fearless beard,
and two scoop shaped spotlights floating behind your head.
Lars, the comb really does follow you everywhere, even on stage.
So here we go.
My time is over.
Thank you very much.
If you want to learn more,
go to.
If you want to learn more.
Go to.
I or just run npx
clicky and and you're ready to go.
Thank you.